Guide to the Dept. of Household Economics and Management extension records, [ca. 1917]-1982,
New York State College of Home Economics. Dept. of Household Economics and Management extension records, [ca. 1917]-1982
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Dept. of Household Economics and Management extension records, [ca. 1917]-1982, 1925-1962 (bulk)
23-18-919
New York State College of Home Economics. Dept. of Household Economics and Management.
6.6 cubic ft.
Surveys, reports, photographs, slides, filmstrips.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Home economics extension records concerning the cities of Buffalo, Rochester, and Syracuse, New York, and most New York State counties, including annual reports and summaries of home economics and management programs carried on by home economics extension specialists from Cornell University.
ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY
From its founding to ca. 1969 the department was called Household Economics and Management. From ca. 1969 to ca. 1977, it was known as the Department of Consumer Economics and Public Policy. After 1977, it has been called the Department of Consumer Economics and Housing.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Home economics extension records concerning the cities of Buffalo, Rochester, and Syracuse, New York, and most New York State counties, including annual reports and summaries of home economics and management programs carried on by home economics extension specialists from Cornell University; requests from counties for assistance with their extension programs from the College of Home Economics; reports from Household Study Clubs, "kitchen conferences," and extension speakers; extension leaders' lesson plans; and related photocopied items. U.S.D.A. Bureau of Home Economics survey of New York farm wives' use of time, June 1925; 40 completed survey forms and fragments; unpublished analysis of 107 survey forms, probably by Jean Warren; and 11 survey forms from an inventory of farm household equipment, 1925. Also, folders on the content and development of an extension program in Farm and Home Management; Agents Training School materials, 1936-1867; photographs, mostly of kitchens, arranged by county and taken under the supervision of Extension faculty in the Department of Household Economics and Management (photos were used for both Extension and resident teaching); and slides and filmstrips of kitchens and kitchen equipment. Record of equipment purchases for the laboratory.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Home Economics. Department of Household Economics and Management.; New York State College of Home Economics. Dept. of Consumer Economics and Public Policy.; United States. Bureau of Home Economics.
Subjects:
Home economics extension work--New York (State); Home economics extension work--New York (State)--Buffalo.; Home economics extension work--New York (State)--Rochester.; Home economics extension work--New York (State)--Syracuse.; Home economics--Study and teaching.; Home economics--Accounting.; Home economics--Equipment and supplies.; Household appliances.; Kitchens--New York (State); Farmers' spouses--New York (State); Housewives--New York (State); Rural women--New York (State); Home economics extension workers.
Form and Genre Terms:
Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Restricted to educational and research purposes.
CONTAINER LIST
- Albany, 1941-1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Allegany, 1921-1960 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Broome, 1927-1960 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
- Cattaraugus, 1923-1960 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
- Cayuga, 1920-1960 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
- Chatauqua, 1922-1960 (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
- Chemung, 1920-1960 (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
- Chenango, 1923-1960 (Box 1, Folder 13-14)
- Clinton, 1940-1960 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Columbia, 1942-1960 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Cortland, 1920-1960 (Box 1, Folder 17-18)
- Delaware, 1923-1960 (Box 1, Folder 19-20)
- Dutchess, 1946-1960 (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Erie, 1921-1960 (Box 1, Folder 22-23)
- Buffalo City, 1935-1955 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Essex, 1948-1960 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Franklin, 1933-1960 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Fulton, 1950-1960 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Genesee, 1919-1960 (Box 1, Folder 28-29)
- Greene, 1949-1960 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Herkimer, 1920-1960 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Jefferson, 1921-1960 (Box 2, Folder 32-33)
- Lewis, 1926-1960 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Livingston, 1928-1960 (Box 2, Folder 35-36)
- Madison, 1920-1960 (Box 2, Folder 37-38)
- Monroe, 1925-1960 (Box 2, Folder 39-40)
- Rochester City (Monroe), 1921-1961 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Montgomery, 1942-1960 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Nassau, 1940-1961 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- New York City (Queens), 1952-1955 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Niagara, 1921-1961 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Oneida, 1920-1960 (Box 2, Folder 46-47)
- Onondaga, 1920-1960 (Box 2, Folder 48-49)
- Syracuse City (Onondaga), 1924-1958 (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Ontario, 1922-1960 (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Orleans, 1928-1960 (Box 2, Folder 52)
- Orange, 1928-1960 (Box 2, Folder 53)
- Oswego, 1924-1960 (Box 3, Folder 54-55)
- Ostego, 1924-1960 (Box 3, Folder 56)
- Rensselaer, 1917-1960 (Box 3, Folder 57)
- Rockland, 1947-1960 (Box 3, Folder 58)
- St. Lawrence, 1925-1960 (Box 3, Folder 59)
- Saratoga, 1919-1960 (Box 3, Folder 60)
- Schenectady, 1940-1960 (Box 3, Folder 61)
- Schoharie, 1939-1960 (Box 3, Folder 62)
- Schuyler, 1922-1960 (Box 3, Folder 63)
- Seneca, 1921-1960 (Box 3, Folder 64)
- Steuben, 1921-1960 (Box 3, Folder 65)
- Suffolk, 1922-1960 (Box 3, Folder 66)
- Sullivan, 1924-1960 (Box 3, Folder 67)
- Tioga, 1919-1960 (Box 3, Folder 68)
- Tompkins, 1924-1960 (Box 3, Folder 69-70)
- Ulster, 1933-1960 (Box 3, Folder 71)
- Warren, 1930-1960 (Box 3, Folder 72)
- Washington, 1942-1960 (Box 3, Folder 73)
- Wayne, 1934-1960 (Box 3, Folder 74)
- Westchester, 1942-1960 (Box 3, Folder 75)
- Wyoming, 1936-1960 (Box 2, Folder 76)
- Yates, 1931-1960 (Box 2, Folder 77)
- Folders on the content and development of an extension program in Farm and Home Management; Agents Training School, 1936-1955 (Box 5)
- Agents Training School, 1956-1968 (Box 6)
- Photographs of kitchens, arranged by county, 1940 (Box 7)
- Photographs of kitchen remodeled at 118 Delaware Avenue, Ithaca; Home of Myron Gustin and Evelyn Davis Fincher., 1953 (Box 7)
- Slides of kitchens and kitchen equipment, filmstrips (Box 8)
- U.S.D.A. Bureau of Home Economics survey of N.Y. farm wives use of time, June, 1925. 40 completed survey forms plus fragments; unpublished analysis of 107 survey forms, probably by Jean Warren; inventory of farm household equipment, 11 survey forms., 1925 (Box 9)